Lev Karatun

Full-stack JavaScript developer

Software engineer with 5 years of experience of teaching web development, data structures and algorithms to university students, as well as writing C++ as part of my PhD research. I'm passionate about new technologies, website performance, and writing clean, testable code.

647-964-2973

Toronto, Canada

levkaratun.com

github.com/lkaratun

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Programming on the web (JavaScript) University of Toronto (Department of Computer Science)

09/2018 - Present

Toronto, Canada

Tasks/Achievements

- Present course material (JavaScript snippets, libraries, browser and node.js features) to students in tutorials.
- Help students with debugging and understanding of web technologies.
- Design and write tests to auto-mark students' assignments.

Introduction to programming (Python)

University of Toronto (Department of Computer Science)

01/2014 - Present

Toronto, Canada

Tasks/Achievements

- Presented data structures and algorithms concepts to students in tutorials.
- Helped students debug the code in practicals and office
- Marked students' exams.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior IT systems engineer CROC Inc.

10/2012 - 08/2013

Moscow, Russia

Achievements/Tasks

- Installed, configured and supported IBM middle-ware applications.
- Administered Linux servers, created snapshots of virtual machines for future use.
- Prepared technical and operational software documentation.

Application Support Specialist JSC "Raiffeisenbank"

06/2010 - 09/2012

Moscow, Russia

Achievements/Tasks

- Created instructions to delegate simple requests (such as password resetting) to the 1st line of support, resulting in a 20% decrease of tickets escalated to the 2nd line of support.
- Provided support for users experiencing problems with software (2nd line of support).
- Collaborated with QA and developers in registering and tracking bugs in the software.

SKILLS

JavaScript HTML5 CSS3

React

node.js

MongoDB

SOL

Pvthon

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Movies data visualization (04/2018 – 10/2018)

- A dashboard visualizing movies data using D3 on the front end and MongoDB + Express running on node.js on the back end.
- Data is presented using three types of diagrams (scatter plot, map, bar chart) that allow for filtering and user interactions.
- https://levkaratun.com/movies_dashboard/

Memory game (05/2018)

- A memory card game powered by React
- https://levkaratun.com/memory_game/

EDUCATION

PhD candidate University of Toronto

09/2013 - Present

Thesis

Numerical modelling of continental collisions

B.Sc. and M.Sc. degrees Moscow State University

09/2004 - 06/2010

Moscow, Russia

Specialization

Computer technologies in geology

ADDITIONAL EDUCATION

MongoDB basics, MongoDB for node.is developers (06/2018 - 09/2018)

MongoDB Univerity

Scientific Computing for Physicists (01/2016 – 05/2016) SciNet HPC Consortium

Ontario High Performance Computing Summer school (06/2014 - 06/2014)

SciNet HPC Consortium

AWARDS

Laurence Curtis Teaching Assistance Award (2016) University of Toronto

Awarded annually to the most outstanding Teaching Assistants in the Department of Earth Sciences.